smartsupp.com 2016-04-16

# Privacy statement | Smartsupp

Smartsupp live chat is developed and operated by Smartsupp.com, s.r.o., VAT ID : CZ03668681 ("Smartsupp"). All user personal information is considered private. Smartsupp does not share any personal information of its users with 3rd parties. 

## Where is personal information stored?

Personal information is stored on Smartsupp servers, which are located in Czech Republic. Czech Republic is a member state of European Union. Data are not stored or being sent outside of European Union in any way. 

## How is personal information secured? 

Smartsupp protects personal information with use of latest industry standards and security measures. Communication between Smartsupp chat module and Smartsupp servers is secured by SSL/TLS encryption (secure sockets layer / transport layer security). Communication between Smartsupp servers and Smartsupp dashboard is also secured by SSL/TLS encryption. Personal information is stored on Smartsupp servers and complies with with TIER 3+ security standard. 

Smartsupp user can access and edit his personal information after signing in his Smartsupp account at dashboard.smartsupp.com. To sign in, the user has to know his login credentials - email address and password. There is no way to access personal information without knowing the login credentials, therefore no unauthorized party can access it. The sign in process - same as the whole account and domain dashboard.smartsupp.com - is also secured with SSL/TLS encryption. 

## What kind of personal information is being collected?

Smartsupp might, but is not obliged to, collect following information. All personal information mentioned below is considered private and is handled according to this privacy statement. 

**1\. User personal information:** personal info of companies or individuals who created an account on Smartsupp.com website and/or are using Smartsupp live chat on their website. Upon account creation user has to fill in his name/company email address and a password. User can change or update this information after signing in his account on dashboard.smartsupp.com. In his account his can also enter further information as job title or personal motto. User can create new agent accounts and enter above mention personal information about his colleagues for the purpose of those agent accounts. If the user decided to activate a paid version of Smartsupp, he is asked to fill in his billing information and contact email for billing purposes. 

Smartsupp payments are handled by external services Gopay and PayPal, which are specialized in processing financial transactions. These external services can ask client to fill in his credit card information, bank account information or other information in order to successfully make a payment for Smartsupp paid account. All personal and financial information mentioned in this paragraph is processed solely by given external service and Smartsupp doesn't have any access to this information neither is it stored on Smartsupp servers. 

**2\. Visitor personal information:** visitors of Smartsupp.com website, or visitors of any website where Smartsupp live chat is used, might enter personal information into the Smartsupp live chat. Visitors can enter the information either in the chat conversation or in a pre-chat form before the conversation starts. This information is also stored Smartsupp servers. 

Every Smartsupp user has access to personal information of visitors of his website, where he is using Smartsupp live chat. Because the visitor provided the personal information on website of the Smartsupp user, this creates a legal relation between the Smartsupp user and visitor of his website. Smartsupp user can access and handle personal information of his visitors collected through Smartsupp live chat placed on his website. Smartsupp user should handle the personal information of his users according to his own privacy statement and/or terms & conditions. Smartsupp is in no way responsible for behavior or acts of Smartsupp users in connection to handling visitor personal information. Protection and handling of visitor personal information collected by the Smartsupp user is in sole responsibility of the Smartsupp user. 

**3\. Technical information:** while using Smartsupp live chat, certain technical data about visitors might be collected by Smartsupp, e.g. IP address, type and version of browser, type and version of operating system, approximate location etc. 

## How do we use Cookie files? 

While using Smartsupp live chat or other Smartsupp services, temporary files, known as Cookie files, can be stored and processed by Smartsupp. By processing cookie files personal information might be collected and linked with the visitor. This personal information is used solely to improve the Smartsupp services. Smartsupp respects privacy of its users and visitors and while processing Cookie files we follow privacy rules of European Union. 

Visitor can prevent collection and storing of Cookie files by browsing the web in Incognito (private) mode, where he remains anonymous. This mode is supported in all modern browsers. By doing so, the user acknowledges that Smartsupp services might not work properly and that use of Smartsupp services can exhibit unexpected behavior. 

## Changes of this privacy statement

Smartsupp reserves the right to change or update this privacy statement without further notice. It's recommended that users check this privacy statement regularly to have the latest information about Smartsupp privacy policy. Up-todate version of this privacy statement can always be found on our website www.smartsupp.com.
